人都去哪儿了？
Where is everyone?
也许他们不知道我们会来吧
Perhaps they weren't expecting us.
医生，对科考队的检查是每年的例行公事
Our arrival was scheduled well in advance, doctor.
这早就在日程中安排好了
The annual check of every scientific expedition is routine.
我和这个科考站的队长罗伯特·乔纳森
I had a subspace contact with a Robert Johnson,
一个小时前进行过一次子空间联络
the leader of this expedition, not an hour ago.
他提到有什么异常吗？
Well, did he report anything wrong?
没说，但是显然有什么不对劲，但我不太肯定
No. Yet there was something wrong. I can't quite pin it down.
他说话前言不搭后语的，思维混乱
His conversation was disjointed, his thoughts a little foggy, unrelated.
契科夫，检查那栋建筑，史波克和我检查这一栋
Chekov! Check that building. Mr. Spock and I will check this one.
其他人四处查看，看看能不能找到什么人
The rest of you, take a look around. See if you can find anyone.
舰长！
Captain!
舰长！舰长！
Captain! Captain!
有个人，长官，在那儿，一个死人
A man, sir, in there. A dead man.
跟我想的一样
Exactly what it looks like.
-  自然死亡，衰老 -  这也太蹊跷了，医生
- Death by natural causes, old age. - That's quite impossible, doctor.
在我们抵达之前，我调取了这个科考站所有人的资料
I ran a personnel check on this entire expedition before we beamed down.
我可以确定，这些人中没有一个…
I assure you that none of them were...
他们是来跟阿尔文告别的
They've come to pay their respects to Alvin.
-  我是寇克舰长 -  你得大声点儿
- I'm Captain Kirk of... - You'll have to speak louder.
我是说，我是联邦星舰进取号舰长寇克
I say, I'm Captain Kirk of the USS Enterprise.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是罗伯特·乔纳森
I'm Robert Johnson.
这是我的太太，伊莱恩
And this is my wife, Elaine.
您高寿？
How old are you?
您多大年纪了？
我，我想想啊
I'm... Let me see.
我今年29，伊莱恩今年
I am 29. And Elaine is...
我今年27
I'm 27.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索这未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange, new worlds,
找寻新的生命与文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：茶包泰迪
校对：喜马拉雅
第二季第十二集
「濒临死亡」
舰长日志，星历3478.2
Captain's log, stardate 3478.2.
在一次前往伽马九头蛇座IV星
On a routine mission to resupply
为科考队提供例行补给的旅途中
the experimental colony at Gamma Hydra IV,
我们发现了一种极不寻常的现象
we discovered a most unusual phenomenon.
科考队的6名成员中，没有一人超过30岁
Of the six members of the colony, none of whom were over 30,
而我们发现其中四人已经过世，而另外两人也已因为衰老而频临死亡
we found four had died, and two were dying... of old age.
乔纳森先生，能听见我说话吗？
Mr. Johnson, can you hear me?
能听得见，我还没聋呢
I can hear you. I'm not deaf yet, you know.
目前还没聋
Not yet.
能告诉我发生了什么吗？
Can you tell me what happened?
发生了什么？
What happened?
你们的仪表有任何数据显示吗？
Did your instruments show anything?
伊莱恩非常漂亮
Elaine was so beautiful.
特别美丽
So beautiful.
相当动人
他能听见你说什么，吉姆，但是他已经理解不了了
He can hear you, Jim, but he doesn't understand.
还是让他休息吧
Let's let him rest.
他们要是清醒了，我就在指挥室
If they seem lucid, I'll be in the Briefing Room.
不用起立，斯托克准将
Stay seated. Commodore Stocker,
因为伽马九头蛇座IV星在你的管理区域内
I've asked you to be a part of this briefing
所以邀请你也参加这次作战会议
because Gamma Hydra IV falls within your administrative area.
我很荣幸，长官
I appreciate that, sir.
华莱士医生，内分泌学专家
Dr. Wallace, as an expert in endocrinology,
希望你能和麦考伊医生合作愉快
I'd appreciate you working very closely with Dr. McCoy.
-  好的，舰长 -  麦考伊医生
- Yes, captain. - And Dr. McCoy,
请你介绍一下情况
would you fill them in?
科考队员正在饱受机体衰老的折磨
Well, the expedition is suffering from extreme old age
他们正在以非常快的速度迅速衰老
and they're growing older by the minute, much older.
而我进行了全面检查却一无所获
My examinations have turned up absolutely nothing.
事实上，我毫无头绪
In fact, I don't have a clue.
史波克，大气和环境有异常吗？
What about the atmosphere and environment, Mr. Spock?
感应器没有检测到任何对人类有害的物质
Sensors reveal nothing which is inimical to human life.
大气层扫描仪只检测到正常量的有害宇宙射线
The atmosphere screens out the usual amount of harmful cosmic rays.
我们目前离联邦和罗慕兰帝国
We're close to the neutral zone
之间的中立区很近
between our Federation and the Romulan Empire.
有没有可能是罗慕兰用这些科考队员做小白鼠
It's possible the Romulans have a new weapon
来试验他们的新型武器
and are using this colony as guinea pigs.
我已经开始着手往这个方向上进行调查了，舰长
I have already begun investigation into that possibility, captain.
很好，我希望大家尽力在自己所知的领域里进行详细调查
Good. I want you all to check out everything in your own departments.
不管你们的想法角度多刁钻，或是多牵强，我都洗耳恭听
No matter how remote, how far-fetched the notion, I want it run down.
我会保持在这个轨道上，直到我们找到答案
We'll stay in orbit until we have the answer. Thank you.
我想你肯定能理解我想尽快抵达星际10号基地
I'm sure you understand that I am anxious to get to Starbase 10
-  以便按时就任 -  是的，准将
- to assume my new post. - Yes, commodore.
我们会尽量保证你按时抵达的
We'll do everything we can to make your due date.
谢谢
Thank you, sir.
医生，有什么我能效劳的吗？
Doctor, is there something I can do for you?
少一点儿冷漠和雷厉风行的舰长做派
Well, be a little less the cool, efficient captain,
多一些老朋友见面的亲热怎么样
and a little more the old friend.
有多久了？
How long has it been?
六年，四个月零几天
Six years, four months and an odd number of days.
你不记得了？
You mean you don't know?
很久了
A long time.
即使一切重新来过，结局也不会有所改变，不是吗？
Things wouldn't change if it started all over again, would it?
你有你的工作，我有我的船舰，我们不会为彼此妥协
You have your job, I have my ship. And neither one of us will change.
这是你说的，我可没这么说
You said it, I didn't.
这么多年了，你就只跟我联系过一次
In all those years, I only heard from you once.
在我丈夫过世的时候的那张星际图
A stargram when my husband died.
我们分手后你从来没问过我为什么会结婚
You know, you never asked me why I got married after we called it off.
我猜你遇到了你的真爱
Well, I supposed that you met someone you loved.
我遇到了一个了不起的男人，我很崇拜他
I met a man I admired, a great man.
他也正好和你的工作在同一领域，你不需要放弃什么
In the same field as you. You didn't have to give up a thing.
是阿，除了你
No. Just you.
寇克舰长，史波克希望您能来一下舰桥
Captain Kirk, Mr. Spock would like to see you on the Bridge.
马上到
I'm on my way.
-  标准轨道，舰长 -  保持
- Standard orbit, captain. - Maintain.
我重新分析了感应器数据，舰长
I've rechecked the sensors, captain.
伽马九头蛇座IV星大气监测出相当于
Gamma Hydra IV checks out as a Class-M planet
M级行星常规级氮氧含量，正常质量
with a conventional oxygen-nitrogen atmosphere, normal mass.
我目前没有发现任何异常之处
I can find nothing at all out of the ordinary.
那天体物理部报告发现的那颗彗星呢？
And the comet that Astrophysics reported?
我们正在进行分析，目前没有相关的结论
We're running checks on it. I've reached no conclusions yet.
这是一颗四处乱窜的彗星，从来没被监测过
The comet was a rogue and has never been investigated.
-  寇克舰长？ -  怎么了，准将？
- Captain Kirk? - Yes, commodore?
星际10号基地的设备
Facilities at Starbase 10 are much more complete
比这里要完善的多
than those onboard ship.
在我看来，我们尽早到那儿应该会对你的调查更有利
Seems to me your investigations would be facilitated if we proceeded there.
-  我会确保基地全力配合你们 -  谢谢
- I assure you all cooperation. - Thank you.
我知道你着急去基地报道
I know you're anxious to get to the base,
但是我们这儿有一些先进的设备
but we have a few facilities of our own here.
进取号能解决现在的问题，我会在轮机室，史波克
The Enterprise will do quite nicely. I'll be in Engineering, Mr. Spock.
保持标准轨道，苏鲁
Maintain standard orbit, Mr. Sulu.
你已经下达过这条指令了，长官
You already gave that command, sir.
那就继续执行吧
Well, follow it.
戈尔韦上尉
Lieutenant Galway.
医生，能跟你说句话吗？
Doctor, may I speak to you for a moment, please?
当然，请说
Of course. Go right ahead.
我知道这么说听上去有些荒谬
Well, I know this is going to sound foolish,
但是，那个，我好想听力上出现了问题
but, well, I seem to be having a little trouble hearing.
应该不是什么大问题
Well, it's probably nothing important.
我之前从来没有过这类的问题
I never had trouble before.
别担心
Well, don't worry about it.
超声波治疗可能就能解决问题了
Perhaps a little hypersonic treatment might clear it up.
谢谢
Thank you.
史波克，进度报告
Progress report, Mr. Spock.
所有检测结果都没有进展，舰长
All research lines negative, captain.
天体物理部最近有彗星经过的报告，去查查看
Astronomical section reports a comet recently passed by. Check into that.
我正在做，舰长，你之前已经给过这个指令了
I am doing that, captain, as per your previous order.
我们之前讨论过
We discussed that earlier.
哦，对，有进展了告诉我，我在医务室
Oh, yes. Let me know what you come up with. I'll be in the Sickbay.
收到
Acknowledged.
最后一个，罗伯特·乔纳森
The last one. Robert Johnson, cause of death:
-  死亡原因：衰老 -  你已经尽力了
- Old age. - You did what you could.
但是没能帮上任何忙
Which adds up to absolutely nothing.
麦考伊医生？这里是史考特，我能过去找你吗？
Dr. McCoy? This is Scott. May I come up and see you?
你其实就是需要补充一些维生素，要是不放心随时都可以过来
All you need are vitamins. But you can come up anyhow.
老骨头，我觉得你有白头发了
Bones, I believe you're getting grey.
你干一天我这活儿试试，你就明白了
You take over my job and see what happens to you.
-  了解，了解 -  你怎么了，吉姆？
- I see what you mean. - What's your problem, Jim?
肩膀，有点儿刺痛，大概是肌肉拉伤了
Shoulder. Just a twinge. Probably muscular strain.
没准你还真说对了，“医生”
You're probably right, doctor.
顺便说一句，我不喜欢你最近的管理方式
By the way, I don't like the way you've been running this ship lately.
好吧，接受你的申诉，检查吧
All right, reprimand received. Go ahead.
吉姆，我觉得应该给你做一次全身体检
Jim, I think we'd better run a complete physical on you.
为什么？
Why?
就是个肌肉拉伤，不是吗？
Just muscular strain, isn't it?
不是，吉姆，是晚期关节炎，而且正在扩散
No, Jim. It's advanced arthritis, and it's spreading.
-  这不可能 -  我可以再检查一遍
- That's impossible. - I can run it through again,
但是结论还是这个
but I'll come up with the same thing.
史考特！
Scotty!
舰长日志，星历3579.4
Captain's log, stardate 3579.4.
被传送到那个星球上的进取号成员
Of the Enterprise personnel who beamed down to the planet's surface,
麦考伊医生，轮机长史考特，史波克
Dr. McCoy, Engineer Scott, Mr. Spock,
戈尔韦上尉和我自己都开始不同程度的呈现衰老的迹象
Lieutenant Galway and myself are all showing definite signs of aging.
只有契科夫少尉没有收到影响
Only Ensign Chekov appears to be normal.
老骨头，进度报告
Report, Bones.
除了契科夫之外，凡是到过那个星球表面的队员
All of us who went down to the surface, with the exception of Chekov,
都出现了不同程度的衰老
are aging at various rates.
以每天30年的速度衰老
Approximately 30 years for each day.
我不知道发病的原因
I don't know what's causing it,
可能是病毒，细菌甚至是恶灵附身，我会尽力找到病因的
virus, bacteria or evil spirits, but I'm trying to find out.
史波克?我需要数据推算
Spock? I asked for some figures.
按照麦考伊医生给我的资料
Based on what Dr. McCoy gave me,
我推算我们只有不到一周的寿命了
I estimate that physically we each have less than a week to live.
并且
Also,
因为我们的智力衰老速度比身体还要快些
since our mental faculties are aging faster than our bodies,
我们的智力很快就会退化到
we will be little better than mental vegetables
比植物人差不多的状态
in a considerably lesser time.
彻底老化？
Total senility?
是的，舰长，迅速衰老
Yes, captain. In a very short time.
竟然是这么个死法
What a way to die.
好吧
All right.
所有设备以及全体科研人员
I want all the research facilities, all the scientific technicians
立刻对此进行全天候研究
to start round-the-clock research immediately.
我需要知道病因以及治愈方法！
I want the answers, and I want the remedy!
就从为什么契科夫没有受到影响开始着手
You might start by finding out why Chekov hasn't been affected.
我会尽全力的
I'm doing what I can.
-  你非常健康 -  我不这么认为，医生
- You're perfectly healthy. - I must differ with you, doctor.
我注意力下降了，这点真挺烦人的
I'm having difficulty concentrating, which is most disturbing.
而且我的视力下降了
My eyesight appears to be failing.
船舰上的温度正常，但与我而言却是越来越冷了
The normal temperature of the ship seems to me to be increasingly cold.
我不是说你没受影响，史波克
I did not say you weren't affected, Mr. Spock.
作为100岁高龄的瓦肯星人而言
You are perfectly healthy.
你的身体非常健康
That is, for any normal Vulcan on the high side of 100.
舰长，我能回到岗位上了吗？
Captain, can I go back to my station?
-  你觉得你能胜任工作吗，史考特？ -  当然能
- Do you feel up to it, Scotty? - Of course I do.
我只是需要稍微休息一下
I just need a wee bit of rest, that's all.
你也可以回去了，戈尔韦上尉
You can leave too, Lieutenant Galway.
戈尔韦上尉
Lieutenant Galway.
啊?你跟我说话吗，医生？
What? You spoke to me, doctor?
是的，我跟你说话呢，我说，你也可以回去了
Yes, I spoke to you. I said that you could leave too.
你干嘛不回到你的舱室然后睡一会儿呢？
Now, why don't you go on down to your quarters and get some sleep?
不，我不要睡觉
No, I don't wanna sleep.
你难道不明白吗?
Can't you understand?
如果我睡着了，谁知道醒来之后会变成什么样？
If I sleep, what will I find when I wake up?
戈尔韦上尉
Lieutenant Galway,
回到你的岗位上继续工作吧
assume your position and start your duties.
谢谢，长官
Thank you, sir.
在这儿挂个镜子可真讨厌
That's a stupid place to hang a mirror.
她比我还年轻10岁呢，可她看上去
She's 10 years younger than I am. She looks...
每个人衰老的速度不一样
People age normally at different speeds.
他为什么没变化？
Why hasn't he aged?
-  我不知道 -  我想知道！
- I don't know. - Well, I wanna know!
是因为他年轻，还是他的血型，遗传，腺体或是基因？
Is it his youth, his blood type, his heritage, his glands, his genes?
他的基因
"His genes."
护士，给契科夫准备一次全面体检
All right, nurse, prepare Chekov for another complete physical.
来吧，少尉，这次不会那么疼了
Come along, ensign. This won't hurt... much.
我保证
Promises.
几年前在毕宿五
A few years ago on Aldebaran III,
我和我先生曾经尝试过混合各种碳水化合物
my husband and I tried various carbohydrate compounds
从而延长植物寿命
to slow down the degeneration of plant life.
那就快试试吧，华莱士大夫
Well, then try that, Dr. Wallace.
-  都试试，但是要快 -  是的，长官
- Try anything, but do it quickly. - Yes, sir.
我在舰桥，随时告诉我契科夫的情况
I'll be on the Bridge. Keep me posted as to Chekov.
我以为你应该在生化实验室，医生
I thought you were on your way to the biochemistry lab, doctor.
我们俩顺路
We're both going the same direction.
那走吧
So we do.
我们知道问题是什么，我们也知道衰老的速度
Look, we know the problem. We know the progress of the affliction.
从逻辑上来说
Therefore, once we find the proper line of research,
只要确定研究方向我们就能找到治愈的方法
it's only logical we find a solution.
你这个口气和我的大副真像
You sound like my first officer.
没有什么解决不了的问题，包括我们之间的
No problem is insoluble, not even ours.
这可听上去没什么逻辑
That didn't spring from logic.
我们之间的关系本来就没什么逻辑可言
Our situation doesn't have its roots in logic.
心灵可不是什么逻辑器官
The heart is not a logical organ.
我和西欧多尔·华莱士结婚的时候，我以为我已经忘了你了
When I married Theodore Wallace, I thought I was over you.
可我错了
I was wrong.
你是什么时候意识到这点的？今天吗？
When did you realise that? Today?
什么？
What?
你丈夫比你大几岁？
How much older was your husband?
-  这有什么区别吗？ -  回答我
- What difference does that make? - Answer me.
26岁
Twenty-six years.
-  有本质的差异啊 -  吉姆，他是个非常优秀的男人
- That's quite a difference. - Jim, he was a brilliant man.
我们当时在一个偏远的哨所一起工作
We were stationed on a lonely outpost. We were working together.
我不想谈他的事，我想谈谈我们
I don't wanna talk about him. I wanna talk about us.
看着我
Look at me.
你看到了什么？
What do you see?
我看到了詹姆士·寇克舰长
I see Captain James Kirk.
一个品行高华，正派体面，英俊潇洒，身强体壮的男人
A man of morality, decency, handsome and strong...
还是个老头子
And old.
-  正在迅速衰老的老头子 -  吉姆，别这么说
- And rapidly growing older. - Jim, please.
你能给我什么呢，珍?
What are you offering me, Jan?
爱情？还是临别礼物？
Love? Or a going-away present?
给我们一些血液样本，契科夫
"Give us some more blood, Chekov.
打针并不疼，契科夫；外衣脱掉，契科夫
The needle won't hurt, Chekov. Take off your shirt, Chekov.
翻个身，契科夫；深呼吸，契科夫
Roll over, Chekov. Breathe deeply, Chekov.
血液样本，契科夫；骨髓样本，契科夫
Blood sample, Chekov. Marrow sample, Chekov.
皮肤样本，契科夫
Skin sample, Chekov."
就算我能活下来，我也会因为样本采集而油尽灯枯的
If... If I live long enough, I'm going to run out of samples.
你会活下来的
You'll live.
是阿，我是会活下来的，但是这么活着又有什么劲阿
Oh, yes, I'll live, but I won't enjoy it.
保持标准轨道，舰长
Maintaining standard orbit, captain.
苏鲁,把近地点高度提升到2万英里
Increase orbit to 20,000 perigee, Mr. Sulu.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
能签个字吗，长官？
Will you sign this, sir?
文书
Yeoman.
斯托克准将，你来舰桥有什么事儿吗？
Do you have a reason for being on the Bridge, Commodore Stocker?
您什么时候方便，我想跟您聊两句
I had hoped for a few words with you at your convenience.
我没有多余的时间
I have very little time.
如果可以的话，我觉得我们应该向星际10号基地出发了
If I may say so, sir, we have a due date at Starbase 10.
我们不太可能按时到达了
We're going to be late.
在解决这里的问题之前，我没打算从这一区域离开
I don't intend to leave this area until we've found a solution for this problem.
舰长，我正眼睁睁的看着
Captain, I am watching four very valuable,
四个优秀的船员以及一个无可替代的舰长饱受摧残
one almost irreplaceable, members of the Starfleet failing before my eyes.
我想做点儿什么能帮上你们
I want to do something to help.
既然你这么焦心，那我就先给星际10号基地发个信息
Since you're so concerned, I'll send a message to Starbase 10.
舰长
Captain,
你今早已经发过信息了
you sent such a message this morning.
文书！那个
Yeoman! Where's that...
-  长官？ -  燃料消耗报告在哪儿？
- Sir? ...fuel consumption report?
我给你了，长官，你已经签完字了
I gave it to you, sir. You signed it.
我要是签过了我还会跟你要吗？
If I had signed it, I wouldn't ask for it, now, would I?
你的签字，舰长
Your signature, captain.
舰长，我觉得
Captain, I believe...
舰长？舰长？
Captain? Captain?
-  史波克，我正在思考 -  是，长官，我能理解
- Spock, I was just thinking. - Yes, sir. Quite understandable.
-  你有什么事儿要报告吗？ -  是的，长官
- You have something to report? - Yes, sir.
我觉得我们已经发现病因了
I believe we have the cause of the affliction.
-  是什么？ -  彗星尾部横穿了
- What is it? - The orbit of Gamma Hydra IV
伽马九头蛇座IV星的运行轨道
carried the planet directly through the comet's trail.
我们通过常规辐射检测什么也没有发现
On conventional radiation settings, we discovered nothing.
直到我们重新设定感应器，把扫描频段降到最低
When resetting our sensors to the extreme lower range of the scale,
这才发现了比正常值低
undetected radiation appeared.
之前没检测到的放射线
Below normal radiation levels, but definitely present,
毫无疑问放射线来自那颗彗星
and undoubtedly residue from the comet.
好的，史波克，非常好
Good, Spock. Well done.
我们马上去跟麦考伊医生汇报
Let's get this to Dr. McCoy immediately.
上尉，给星际舰队指挥部发消息
Lieutenant, take a message to Starfleet Command.
-  是的，长官 -  这里离罗慕兰星很近
- Aye, sir. - Due to the proximity of the Romulans,
最好使用2号代码
better use Code 2.
但是舰长，罗慕兰人已经破译了2号代码
But, captain, the Romulans have broken Code 2.
-  上次公告里 -  那就用3号代码
- If you remember the last bulletin... - Then use Code 3.
-  是的，长官，3号代码 -  内容
- Yes, sir, Code 3. - Message:
导致衰老的原因可能是，彗星穿过伽马九头蛇座IV星轨道
Key to affliction may be comet which passed by Gamma Hydra IV.
彗星现在位于
Said comet is now...
- 448象限，长官 -  象限
- Quadrant 448, sir. - Quadrant...
所有单位对辐射进行全面分析并找到中和方法
All units are to be alerted for complete analysis of radiation
并对这颗极度危险的彗星保持警觉
and means found to neutralise it. The comet is highly dangerous.
进取号指挥官寇克
Kirk, commanding Enterprise.
-  上尉，马上发出，我们走把 -  是，长官
- Immediately, lieutenant. Let's go. - Aye, sir.
哦，苏鲁
Oh, Mr. Sulu,
近地点高度增加2万英里
increase orbit to 20,000-mile perigee.
你是说再增加2万英里吗,舰长？
You mean another 20,000, captain?
我就不明白了，为什么我每下达一个指令都有这么多质疑？
I fail to understand why each one of my commands is being questioned.
苏鲁，按我说的做
Now, do as you're told, Mr. Sulu.
苏鲁，报告你现在的坐标
Mr. Sulu, what is our present position?
轨道高度2万英里，长官
Orbiting at 20,000, sir.
-  保持 -  保持，长官
- Maintain. - Maintaining, sir.
辐射，这个结论不错
Radiation. Well, that's as good an answer as any,
可是为什么我们之前没发现？
but why didn't we know about it earlier?
医生，很可能是因为
Possibly, doctor, because my thinking processes
我的思维变迟钝了
are not as efficient as before.
检测一遍这个，医生
Run this through, doctor.
老骨头，我回舰桥了，有消息告诉我，史波克？
All right, Bones. I'm going up to the Bridge. Keep me posted. Spock.
我有个问题要问医生
I have a question for the doctor.
医生，船舰上的温度已经变得让我觉得非常不舒服了
Doctor, the ship's temperature is increasingly uncomfortable for me.
即使我已经把舱室的温度调高到51度了
I've adjusted the environment in my quarters to 125 degrees,
也仅仅是勉强能接受，但是，我
which is at least tolerable. However, l...
我可不会再给你上门应诊了
Well, I see I'm not gonna be making any house calls on you.
我想知道有没有什么东西
I wondered if perhaps there was something
能降低我对寒冷的敏感性
which could lower my sensitivity to cold.
我不是魔术师，史波克，我就是个蒙古大夫
I'm not a magician, Spock, just an old country doctor.
这倒是，和我之前怀疑的一样
Yes. As I always suspected.
麦考伊医生，我们常用的治疗辐射的方法
Dr. McCoy, none of our usual radiation therapies
对这些症状都没有反应
will have any effect on this radiation sickness.
那就从头再来，只能这样，我们必须更努力
Well, then we just start over, that's all. We work harder,
更快，有必要的话我们从头来
faster, and we start completely from scratch if we have to.
但是我们必须得有解决方法
But we find something.
史波克，我能跟你聊聊吗？
Spock, can I have a word with you?
-  准将？ -  史波克，即使首席轮机长和首席医生
- Commodore? - Mr. Spock, a starship can function
甚至大副的身体状况都不好
with a chief engineer and a chief medical officer,
但这艘星舰照样可以正常运行
even a first officer, under physical par.
可是，如果船舰指挥官身体情况不佳
But it is disastrous to have a commanding officer
那后果将是灾难性的
whose condition is any less than perfection.
-  我知道 -  请你谅解
- I am aware of that. - Please understand me.
我非常崇拜寇克舰长，他是个非常了不起的指挥官
My admiration for Captain Kirk is unbounded. He is a great officer.
但是，史波克，我需要你的帮助和配合
But, Mr. Spock, I need your help and your cooperation.
哪方面，长官？
For what, sir?
我希望你能接管进取号的指挥权
I would like you to take over command of the Enterprise.
理由是什么，准将？
On what grounds, commodore?
理由就是，舰长备受病痛折磨
On the grounds that the captain, because of his affliction,
已经无法履行他的职责了
is unable to perform his duties.
请允许我提醒你，长官，我也在备受病痛折磨
Need I remind you, sir, that I too have contracted the same affliction?
没错，但是你是瓦肯星人，你比人类寿命长的多
Yes, but you're a Vulcan. You have a much greater life span.
病痛对你的影响要比其他人小得多
You show the effects to a much smaller degree.
我有一半人类的血源，长官
I am half human, sir.
我的身体反应机能下降，思维缓慢
My physical reflexes are down, my mental capacities reduced,
我容易疲劳
I tire easily.
不，长官，我不适合接替指挥官
No, sir. I am not fit for command.
如果连你这个瓦肯星人的身体都吃不消的话
Well, if you are not with your Vulcan physique,
那么很显然，寇克舰长就更不行了
then obviously Captain Kirk cannot be.
长官，我还有工作要继续
Sir, I do have duties to perform.
史波克
Mr. Spock.
我也不愿意这么说，但是规程就是这么要求的
I do not like what I am about to say but regulations demand it,
作为星际舰队的将级军官，我必须严格遵从规程
and as a Starfleet flag officer, I must follow regulations.
作为进取号的大副
As second-in-command of the Enterprise,
你必须马上召集一个临时指挥能力听证会
you must convene an extraordinary competency hearing.
我拒绝这个建议，准将
I resist that suggestion, commodore.
你没得选
It's not a matter of choice.
当舰长身体或思维出现异常时
When a captain is unfit physically or mentally,
临时指挥能力听证会强制召开
a competency hearing is mandatory.
别逼着我引经据典，你和我一样都熟悉那些规程
Don't make me quote a regulation which you know as well as I do.
很好，长官
Very well, sir.
听证会会在下午2点召开
The hearing shall convene at 1400 hours.
-  这回不会那么疼了 -  上次你就这么说了
- Now, this isn't gonna hurt a bit. - That's what you said the last time.
-  疼吗？ -  疼
- Did it hurt? - Yes.
医生
Doctor...
老骨头
Bones.
她死了
She's dead.
她的新陈代谢导致她比我们更快速地衰老了
Her metabolism caused her to age more rapidly than the rest of us,
我们也会步她的后尘，除非
but the same thing's gonna happen to us unless...
老骨头，我们还有多少时间？
How long have we got, Bones?
大概几天
A matter of days,
也可能几个小时
perhaps hours.
事先说明，这次临时听证会是应斯托克准将要求
Let it read that this competency hearing was ordered by Commodore Stocker
在我并不情愿的前提下召开的
and reluctantly called by myself.
还要说明，我认为这个听证会是无效的
Let it also read that I consider it invalid.
史波克，我能发言吗？
Mr. Spock, may I make a statement?
我在不得已的情况下，只能借助规章制度
I have had to resort to these legal grounds in order to save the lives
从而挽救星际舰队的重要成员以及船上各位的性命
of some very valuable members of the Starfleet.
我一直试图劝说寇克舰长
I have tried to convince Captain Kirk
有必要前往星际10号基地
of the necessity of proceeding to Starbase 10,
但是每次要求都被驳回了
but have been overruled in each case.
召开这次听证会的责任在我
The responsibility of this hearing is mine.
恰恰相反，准将
On the contrary, commodore,
作为会议主席以及进取号大副
as presiding officer and second-in-command of the Enterprise,
这个责任在我
the responsibility is mine.
寇克舰长，你要发言吗？
Captain Kirk, would you like to make a statement?
是的，我有话要说
Yes, I would like to make a statement.
我是这艘船舰的指挥官，并且我完全有能力指挥她
I am the captain of this ship and I'm totally capable of commanding her.
大家还是赶紧结束这个破玩意儿，回去工作吧
Let's call this whole thing off and get back to work.
这不可能，舰长，规程对此有明确要求
It's quite impossible, captain. The regulations are quite specific.
在听证委员会召集所有证人之后
You are entitled to direct examination of all witnesses
你必须立刻接受质询
immediately after the board has questioned them.
我谢谢你，史波克！
That's very kind of you, Spock.
苏鲁，你和寇克舰长一起共事多久了？
Mr. Sulu, how long have you served with Captain Kirk?
-  两年了，长官 -  就你所知
- Two years, sir. - To your knowledge,
他是那种优柔寡断，做事瞻前顾后的人吗？
has he ever had any difficulty making decisions?
不是，长官
No, sir.
他是不是给你指令要求保持在伽马九头蛇座IV星标准轨道上?
Did he order you to maintain standard orbit around Gamma Hydra IV?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
他是不是在几分钟后又再一次重复了这一指令？
Did he not, several minutes later, repeat that order?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
-  他是不是给你指令要增加轨道近地点？ -  是的，长官
- Did he order you to increase orbit? - Yes, sir.
他是不是在几分钟后又再一次重复了这一指令？
Did he not, several minutes later, repeat that order?
他没有！
He did not!
我发出了指令并且确定指令会被执行的话
When I give an order, I expect it to be obeyed.
我就没必要再重复一遍自己的话
I don't have to repeat myself.
苏鲁
Mr. Sulu,
请你回答刚才的问题
you'll please answer the question.
是的，长官，寇克舰长重复了这一指令
Yes, sir. Captain Kirk repeated his order.
谢谢，苏鲁
Thank you, Mr. Sulu.
阿特金斯文书
Atkins.
你当着在做这些证人的面，递给了寇克舰长
You handed Captain Kirk a fuel-consumption report
一份耗油量报告，他看完后签字了
in the presence of witnesses, which he read and signed.
是这样的吗？
Is that correct?
长官，他当时正在考虑更重要的问题
Sir, he had more important things on his mind.
-  目前 -  文书
- The present... - Yeoman,
请直接回答我的问题
you will simply answer the question.
我，我猜他不记得自己签过字了
L... I guess he forgot he'd signed it.
你猜?
You guess?
他不记得自己签过字了
He forgot he'd signed it.
谢谢，文书，你可以回去工作了
Thank you, yeoman. You may leave.
乌乎拉上尉
Lieutenant Uhura.
我这儿有一份星际舰队指挥部公告
I have here a bulletin from Starfleet Command
上面提到罗慕兰人已经破解了2号代码
which states that the Romulans had broken Code 2.
底下是你的签名吗？
Are these your initials which appear at the bottom?
是的
They are.
你下面的签字是谁的？
And whose initials are those which appear directly below yours?
这些是寇克舰长的
Those of Captain Kirk.
寇克舰长是不是要求你将彗星
Did Captain Kirk ask you to send a message about the comet
穿过伽马九头蛇座IV星的消息发出去？
which passed Gamma Hydra IV?
-  是的 -  使用2号代码？
- He did. - Using Code 2?
是的，但是他马上就改口说使用3号代码了
Oh, yes, but he changed it to Code 3.
这一更改是在你提醒他罗慕兰人已经破解2号代码后
After you reminded him that the Romulans had broken Code 2.
-  是的 -  谢谢，上尉
- Yes. - Thank you, lieutenant.
麦考伊医生
Dr. McCoy.
在呢，在呢，史波克，干嘛？
Yeah. Yes, Mr. Spock, what is it?
几小时前，依照委员会的要求
Several hours ago, at the request of this board,
你为寇克舰长做了一次全面的体检
you ran a complete physical examination of Captain Kirk.
是的
I did.
医疗数据库，使用已有的标准值作为比对
Medical banks. Compute, describe subject's physical age,
计算，描述该对象实际生理年龄
using established norms as comparative base.
处理中，根据各项生理数据
Working. Subject's physical age, based on physiological profile,
该对象生理年龄在60-72岁，正在迅速老化
between 60 and 72, aging rapidly.
我今年才三十，三十四岁
Oh, I'm thirty-f... I'm 34 years old.
计算机的数据不这么认为，舰长
The computer differs with you, captain.
-  麦考伊医生 -  干嘛？
- Dr. McCoy. - Yes?
请你从专业角度上对寇克舰长
Will you give us your professional evaluation
现在的身体情况给出评估？
of Captain Kirk's present physical condition?
寇克舰长目前正在遭受
Captain Kirk is suffering from
罕见的身体机能退化的折磨
a peculiar physical degeneration
这种退化近似于衰老
which strongly resembles aging.
他的思维能力是不是退化的更为迅速？
Is not his mental capacity degenerating even more rapidly?
-  是的，但是他目前情况还不错 -  医生
- Yes, but he's a better man now... - Doctor,
你听到了计算机对寇克舰长生理年龄的分析
you heard the computer's analysis of Captain Kirk's physical age.
你认同这个分析结果吗？
Do you agree with it?
去你的计算机，史波克，你不能和一个机器讨论问题吧
Blasted machines. Spock, you can't argue with a machine.
你认同这个分析结果吗，医生？
Do you agree with it, doctor?
是的，我认同
Yes. Yes, I do agree.
我很抱歉，吉姆
And I am sorry, Jim.
委员会没有其它问题要质询了
This board has no further questions.
斯托克准将，不知道你是不是还有其他问题
Unless you, Commodore Stocker, have something you would like to add.
没有了，质询结果我很满意，史波克
No. I am quite satisfied, Mr. Spock.
你准备找其它证人吗，寇克舰长？
Do you wish to call any witnesses, Captain Kirk?
我完全有能力为自己辩护，史波克
I'm perfectly capable of speaking in my own defence, Mr. Spock.
-  舰长，我建议 -  不，没关系，史波克，我能行
- Captain, I would suggest... - No, it's all right, Spock. It's all right.
开这个听证会其实原因只有一个
There's only one reason, and one reason alone
因为我拒绝离开伽马九头蛇座II星
for having this hearing. I refuse to leave Gamma Hydra II.
伽马九头蛇座IV星，舰长
Gamma Hydra IV, captain.
没错，口误
Yes. A slip of the tongue.
你已经没办法记住你曾经所下达过得指令
Captain, your inability to remember having given commands,
读过和签过的重要文件了
reading and signing important orders and then forgetting them,
而你自己的首席医生也得出了身体机能分析结果
your physical analysis as compiled by your own chief surgeon,
这些证据都无可辩驳的证明了
all of these things would appear to be irrefutable proof
你的身体和思维机能已经退化了
of failing physical and mental condition.
那我想问问，在这样的情况下谁会不受影响呢？
So I'm a little confused. Who wouldn't be at a time like this?
我的船舰遇到了麻烦，我的船员饱受病痛折磨
My ship's in trouble, my senior officers are ill,
是个人都有可能被
and this nonsense about a competency hearing
这个什么乱七八糟的能力听证会绕进去
is enough to mix up any man.
试图解雇一个在任的舰长
Trying to relieve a captain of his command is...
实在是，什么来的，是，是
Why, that's... That's...
史波克
Spock.
我简直不敢相信你会这么对我
I wouldn't have believed it of you.
来吧，问我问题
Go ahead. Ask me questions.
我会证明我的能力的，我的记忆力完全没问题
I'll show you what I'm capable of. Nothing wrong with my memory.
来吧，问什么都行
Go ahead, ask me anything.
我们现在正在伽马九头蛇座II星轨道上，对吧？
We're in orbit around Gamma Hydra II, right?
总之，都不是问题
Anyhow, it doesn't matter.
指挥一艘星舰远比
There's a lot more to running a starship
回答一堆愚蠢的问题要复杂得多
than answering a lot of fool questions.
复杂的多
A lot more.
-  来吧，问我问题吧 -  我们已经没什么要问的了，舰长
- Go ahead, ask me a question. - We have no more questions, captain.
问我什么都行
Ask me anything.
随便什么都行
Anything.
不会再有其他问题需要质询了，舰长
There will be no more questions, captain.
如果可以的话，希望你离开这里，委员会需要投票表决
If you would leave the room so the board can vote...
好主意，赶紧投票赶紧结束
Good idea. Get this stupid voting over with
这样我就可以回去工作了
so I can get back to running the ship.
再没见过这么蠢的事儿了
Worst fool thing I ever heard of.
一堆事儿要处理，居然还有闲心开什么听证会
Competency hearing when there's work to be done.
我会在我的舱室里等着你们的决定
I'll be in my quarters awaiting your decision.
鉴于几位高级指挥官身体条件也无法胜任
Well, since the senior officers are incapable,
作为将级军官，按照规程，将由我来接替指挥
and I am of flag rank, I am forced by regulations to assume command.
长官，你从来没有指挥过一艘星舰
Sir, you have never commanded a starship.
那你说怎么办，史波克
What would you have, Mr. Spock,
找一个实际经验比我还少的尉官吗?
a junior officer with far less experience than I have?
-  罗慕兰星的威胁还在 -  我们必须要挽救这些人
- The danger from the Romulans... - We have to save these people.
苏鲁
Mr. Sulu.
设定去星际10号基地的直航航线，曲速5
Set a direct course for Starbase 10. Warp 5.
-  穿过中立区吗? -  马上执行，苏鲁
- Across the neutral zone? - Immediately, Mr. Sulu.
所有人回到自己的岗位上
All officers are to return to their posts.
史波克？
Spock?
是的，舰长
Yes, captain.
所以，我被解职了是吧
So I've been relieved.
-  我很抱歉，舰长 -  是啊
- I'm sorry, captain. - Yes.
你应该去做个检察官
You should have been a prosecuting attorney.
-  规程要求 -  规程
- Regulations required... - Regulations.
别跟我说什么规程
Don't give me regulations.
你觊觎指挥权很久了，你一直想找借口
You've wanted command all along. The first little excuse you get...
-  舰长，不是我接替指挥 -  我真希望你能…
- Captain, I've not assumed command. - I hope you're proud of the...
什么意思，不是你接替指挥？
What do you mean, you've not assumed command?
-  我和你一样也在饱受老化的痛苦 -  如果你不接替指挥，那是谁？
- I suffer the same affliction as you. - If you're not in command, who is?
-  斯托克准将 -  斯托克？
- Commodore Stocker. - Stocker?
你疯啦？
Are you crazy?
-  他从来没实战指挥过 -  史考特也没办法胜任指挥
- He's never had a field command. - Mr. Scott was unfit for command.
斯托克准将作为一个将级军官
Commodore Stocker, as ranking officer...
别跟我扯什么官阶！
Don't... Don't talk to me about rank!
那就是个纸上谈兵夸夸其谈的人！
The man's a chair-bound paper-pusher!
-  我命令你去接替指挥权 -  我不能，舰长
- I order you to take command. - I cannot, captain.
-  你是准备抗命了？ -  不是，长官
- Are you refusing a direct order? - No, sir.
目前船上只有斯托克准将才能下达指令了
Only Commodore Stocker can give a command order onboard this ship.
你这个叛变了的
You traitorous...
叛徒
...disloyal...
你一有机会就从背后冲我捅刀子
You stab me in the back the first chance you get.
史波克
Spock.
出去
Get out.
我不想看见你了
I never wanna have to look at you again.
珍
Jan.
吉姆，对不起，真的，我很抱歉
Oh, Jim, I'm sorry. Truly, I am.
我做了件蠢事
I made a fool of myself in there.
我不应该由着他们指责我，跟我绕圈子
I shouldn't have let them confuse me, rattle me.
大家都明白
Everybody understood.
我不是个老糊涂，珍，我不是
But I'm not old, Jan. I'm not.
一些肌肉疼痛不会让人衰老的
A few muscular aches doesn't make a man old.
开星舰不是用四肢而是用头脑
You don't run a starship with your arms, you run it with your head.
我脑子一直都很清楚
And my brain's as sharp as it ever was.
就因为一点儿辐射副反应就让我解职了？
A simple case of radiation poisoning, they relieve me of my command?
我承认我头发有些花白了 但是换你受了辐射也会这样的
I admit I'm getting a little grey, but radiation will do that to you.
-  原谅我，我还有工作要做 -  珍
- Forgive me, I have some work to do. - Jan.
你了解我，仔细看看我
You know me. Look at me closely.
告诉我
Tell me,
我已经变老了吗？
am I getting old?
你到这儿来干嘛？
What are you doing here?
这才是我能帮上忙的地方
It would seem to be the place where I can be of the most use.
你是不是打算也把麦考伊医生解职了？
Maybe you'd like to relieve Dr. McCoy?
-  契科夫那儿怎么样了？ -  没发现，什么都没发现
- What about Chekov? - Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
老骨头，肯定有什么，我们一起被传送下去的
Bones, there has to be. There has to be. We beamed down together.
我们一起站在那儿
We were on the surface together on the same spot.
-  我们一直在一起行动 -  不对，不是一直都在一起的，舰长
- We were together all the time. - No, not all the time, captain.
-  他跟我们分开了一段时间 -  他跟我们分开过？他跟我们分开过
- He left us for a few moments. - He left us? He left us.
他去了那栋建筑物
He went into the building.
史波克，在那儿发生了什么
Spock, something happened.
是的，是的，确实，舰长
Yes. Yes, indeed, captain.
医生，你再想想
Doctor, you will remember...
他很害怕，他看见了那具死尸
He was scared. He saw the dead body.
然后他从那栋建筑物里跑出来，他怕得要死
And he ran out of the building and he was scared to death.
是的，是的，那么，那可能就是原因
Yes. Yes, now that... That could be.
惊吓，害怕
Frightened, scared.
心跳过速，呼吸急促
Heart beats faster, breath gets short,
出冷汗，肾上腺素激增
and has cold sweats. Adrenaline flows.
肾上腺活跃
Adrenal activity.
等一下，我以前读到过
Now, hold on just a minute now. There's something that I read once.
在古代史里
It was ancient history,
原子时代之后
just after the atomic age.
肾上腺素
Used for radiation sickness.
曾经用来治疗辐射！
Adrenaline!
医生，海若琳是目前治疗辐射病的广谱药物
Doctor, hyronalin is the specific accepted for all radiation sickness.
是的，是的，那是现在
Yes. Yes, now.
但是在这之前，肾上腺素
But before, adrenaline. Highly promising.
曾经在早期研究中很被看好
Early research.
但是在发现海若琳后放弃了对它的继续研究
But they abandoned it when hyronalin was discovered.
很有可能，医生
Quite possible, doctor.
也许我们能研制出一种有效的混合试剂
Perhaps a sufficiently efficacious compound could be developed.
别光站在那儿动嘴说了，史波克，你和华莱士医生赶紧去研制
Don't just stand there jawing, Spock. You and Dr. Wallace get cracking!
进入罗慕兰中立区，长官
Entering Romulan Neutral Zone, sir.
所有感应器调制最大
All sensors on maximum.
谢谢，苏鲁
Thank you, Mr. Sulu.
乌呼拉上尉，如果联系上任何罗慕兰人就通知我
Lieutenant Uhura, let me know if we contact any Romulan.
我认为我们已经联系上了
I think we just made contact, sir.
罗慕兰人从两边夹击我们，长官
Romulans approaching from both sides, sir.
-  我们被包围了，长官 -  轮机室在等候指令，长官
- We're bracketed, sir. - Engineering wants instructions, sir.
斯托克准将，你的指令是什么？
Commodore Stocker, what are your orders?
准将！
Commodore!
-  我要去舰桥 -  不行，吉姆，你不能去
- I'm going up to the Bridge. - No, Jim, you can't do it.
我必须去，我们被袭击了
I've got to go. We're under attack.
护士！华莱士医生！
Nurse! Dr. Wallace!
-  让我去 -  吉姆，你不能去
- Let me go. - Jim, you can't.
我们被袭击了，我必须去舰桥
We're under attack. I have to go to the Bridge.
我必须去舰桥
I've got to go to the Bridge.
-  继续联系罗慕兰人 -  我正在努力，准将
- Keep trying to raise the Romulans. - I'm trying, commodore.
如果可以和他们对话
If I could talk to them,
我会解释我们为什么会闯入中立区
explain to them why we violated the neutral zone...
长官，罗慕兰人可是以从不接受解释辩解而著称的
The Romulans are notorious for not listening to explanations, sir.
乌呼拉上尉是对的，长官，我们之前曾和他们有过纠纷
Lieutenant Uhura is right, sir. We've tangled with them before.
这个菜鸟，在那儿折腾我的船
Greenhorn up there, ruining my ship.
-  吉姆，我必须给你打针让你镇定下来 -  不行
- Jim, if I have to give you a shot... - No.
吉姆，小子，你就老实躺着吧
Jim, boy, you just lay quiet.
你去了也是白搭，咱俩心知肚明
You can't do no good. We're both through.
不行
No.
不行，我的船
No. My ship.
我的船
My ship.
医生，这个血清只是采用了基础测算和配方
Doctor, make the necessary computations and produce this serum.
制作的太粗糙了，副作用也可能很危险，但我们没时间改进
It is crude and dangerous. We had no time for refinements.
好吧，我们试试吧
All right. Let's... Let's go.
这可能是治愈，也可能是致命，医生
It could cure or kill, doctor.
别跟我来那套瓦肯星人的絮叨，史波克
Don't give me any Vulcan details, Spock.
-  赶紧给我打血清 -  不对
- Just give me the shot. - No.
-  我应该打第一针 -  你不行
- I'll take the first shot. - You can't.
你觉得找这么撞下去这艘船舰还能坚持多久？
How long do you think this ship can take the pounding?
我必须赶紧好起来
I've got to get up there.
-  吉姆，这可能会害死你的 -  横竖都是一死
- Jim, it could kill you. - I'll die anyway.
打吧
Do it.
华莱士医生，给他注射吧
Dr. Wallace, give him the shot.
快点儿
Quickly.
赶紧的
长官，他们开始新一轮进攻
Sir, they fired another.
怎么样了？
Well, well, what's happening?
已经停止继续老化了
The aging process has stopped.
他的身体机能开始恢复
His bodily functions are getting stronger.
长官，我已经尝试了所有的呼叫频段，他们完全无视我们
Sir, I've tried all known hailing frequencies. They simply ignore us.
你的意见，苏鲁
Opinion, Mr. Sulu.
他们知道我们已经无力反击了
They know they have us.
他们也清楚我们的护盾快要耗尽了
They know our shields will give out.
那我们除了投降别无选择了
Well, then we have no alternative but to surrender.
长官，罗慕兰人不接受俘虏
Sir, the Romulans do not take captives.
-  失去动力，长官 -  我该怎么办？
- We're losing power, sir. - What am I going to do?
我得做点儿什么阿
I've got to do something.
报告，苏鲁
Report, Mr. Sulu.
我们被至多10艘罗慕兰船舰包围了
We're surrounded by Romulan vessels, maximum of 10.
范围：50到100000公里
Range: 50 to 100,000 kilometres.
轮机室，这里是舰长，启动所有备用动力
Engineering, this is the captain. I want full emergency power.
必须在两分钟内准备就绪
I want everything within about two minutes.
曲速动力引擎全部待命，完毕，寇克
I want the warp-drive engines on full standby. Kirk out.
用特殊频道与星际舰队指挥部联系
Open up a special channel to Starfleet Command.
-  是，长官 - 2号代码
- Aye, sir. - Code 2.
但是，舰长，代码
But, captain, Code...
这是命令，上尉，2号代码
That's an order, lieutenant. Code 2.
-  是，舰长，2号代码 -  内容
- Yes, captain, Code 2. - Message:
发件人：进取号，收件人：此星域星际舰队指挥部
From Enterprise to Starfleet Command, this sector.
由于无意中闯入罗慕兰中立区
Have inadvertently encroached upon Romulan Neutral Zone.
我舰遭受罗慕兰人的围追和猛烈攻击
Surrounded and under heavy Romulan attack.
无法脱身，护盾失效
Escape impossible, shields failing.
将采用最新安装的科波麦特启动自毁程序
Will implement destruct order using corbomite device recently installed.
进取号的这一自毁行为
Since this will result in the destruction of the Enterprise
将会波及到直径20万公里的区域
and all matter within a 200,000-kilometre diameter,
并造成区域通信完全中断
and establish a corresponding dead zone,
请所有联邦船舰在四个太阳年之内避免进入这一区域
all Federation ships will avoid this area for the next four solar years.
爆炸倒计时60秒，寇克，进取号指挥官，完毕
Explosion will take place in one minute. Kirk, commanding Enterprise. Out.
苏鲁，航向188，坐标14
Mr. Sulu, course: 1-8-8 degrees, mark 14.
速度：曲速8
Speed: Warp factor 8.
-  准备就绪 -  准备就绪，长官
- Stand by. - Standing by, sir.
罗慕兰人撤退了，舰长
Romulans giving ground, captain.
显然如你所料，他们中计了
Obviously they tapped in as you expected them to.
史波克，这是逻辑的推断，他们还在继续撤退吗？
A logical assumption, Spock. Are they still retreating?
-  是的，长官 -  很好
- Yes, sir. - Good.
全体人员，准备就绪
All hands, stand by.
曲速8前进
Warp factor 8, now.
罗慕兰人放松了警惕，舰长
The Romulans were caught off-guard, captain.
-  他们远远被甩开了 -  我们已经冲出包围圈了吗，苏鲁?
- They're falling behind. - Are we out of range, Mr. Sulu?
-  是的，长官，并且已经离开了中立区 -  解除红色警报
- Yes, sir. And out of the neutral zone. - Secure from red alert.
设定新航线257，坐标3
Adjust to new course. 2-5-7 degrees, mark 3,
前往星际10号基地
heading for Starbase 10.
航线257，坐标3
2-5-7 degrees, mark 3.
舰长，我想跟你解释一下，我这么做
Captain, I just wanted to assure you that I did what I thought best
-  完全是为了解救你和这些船员们 -  听见了
- to save both you and the men. - Noted.
但是，你也应该清楚
You should know, however,
星际基地的能力和星舰比并没有那么大的优势
that there's very little a starbase can do that a starship can't.
舰长，请允许我这么说，我现在已经非常清楚
If I may say so, captain, I am now quite aware of what a starship can do
在一个称职的舰长指挥下，一艘星舰的能力
with the right man at the helm.
医生，你看上去不错
You're looking good, doc.
我觉得没事儿了，史考特也是，血清起作用了
I'm feeling fine. So is Scotty. The serum worked.
在恢复过程中他拉伤了肌肉，除此以外他一切都好
He pulled a muscle during the reaction, but otherwise he's feeling fine.
-  你自己呢？ -  非常好
- And yourself? - Oh, very well.
这儿和那里有些小淤青
A few bruises here and there.
史波克，你准备好了就来注射血清吧
Anytime you're ready, Mr. Spock.
我已经准备好了，医生
I am quite ready now, doctor.
因为你这个瓦肯人的体质
Because of your Vulcan physique,
我给你准备了增强版
I've prepared an extremely potent shot for you.
并且告诉你，我已经把医务室里易碎的东西都收好了
I thought you might like to know I've removed the breakables from Sickbay.
医生，你真体贴
That is very considerate of you, doctor.
我觉得你听到这个会很高兴
I thought you'd be pleased to hear that.
先生们，总之，等到我们老了会回忆起这段经历
Gentlemen, all in all, an experience we'll remember in our old age,
我希望，短时间不用再重温了
which won't be for some while, I hope.
苏鲁，你来接管，匀速行驶
Take over, Mr. Sulu. Steady as she goes.
-  匀速行驶，舰长 -  我记得我刚说过
- Steady as she goes, captain. - I thought I said that.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF微博http://weibo.com/tlfsubs/
TLF中文字幕站http://subs.eastgame.org/